### **ABHINAV DAMLE**

### DATA ANALYST

**☎**+353 0894746094 | ⊠abhinavdx7@gmail.com |

Apartment 10, Green park student accommodation, Dundalk A91E651.

### **SUMMARY:**

I am a versatile **Data Scientist** with a strong background in NLP and data analysis. Currently interning at **Adapt in Dublin**, Ireland, I am fine-tuning GPT models for an AI chatbot project, integrating it into websites using Flask, and critically assessing AI model performance and ethical implications. My experience also includes excelling in sales at **Three IE, Dundalk, Ireland**, where I consistently met and exceeded sales targets and received multiple "Employee of the Month" awards. In my previous roles as a **Data Analyst at Truecaller and Edgate Technologies**, I honed my data analysis skills, using SQL, data visualization, and statistical analysis to provide data-driven insights for product improvement and strategic planning.

### **SKILLS:**

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS:**

SQL,, API, VISUAL STUDIO CODE, PYTHON, KPI, TABLEAU, DASH, ETL, MICROSOFT WORD, PROGRAMMING LANGAUAGES, POWER BI, DATA MODELING, MACHINE LEARNING, ARTIFICIAL INTELLIENCE, R, ENGINEERING, POWERPOINT, CLOUD, DATA MINING, KPIS, MICROSOFT OFFICE, GIT, SNOWFLAKE , REGRESSION

#### **SOFT SKILLS:**

Motivated, Problem-Solving, Analytical Skills, Data Management, Data Processing, Data Collection, Analyze Data, Statistics, Forecasting, Mathematics, Automation, Reporting and Billing, Finance, Marketing Analytics, Azure ML, Oracle CC&B, Salesforce, Communication Skills, Presentation Skills, Report Writing, Team Player, Sales Strategy, Business Analytics, Sales Operations, Teamwork

### **WORK EXPERIENCE:**

# DATA SCIENTIST | ADAPT (June 2023 - Current)

- Currently engaged in an NLP project focused on building an artificial intelligence chatbot. My role
  involves fine-tuning a GPT model using the GPT API, this process involves optimizing the model's
  parameters and hyperparameters to make it more contextually relevant and effective in generating
  human-like responses. It requires a deep understanding of the model architecture and extensive
  experimentation to achieve the desired chatbot performance.
- Implementation of various NLP techniques, such as Sentiment Analysis, Text Classification, and Summarization. These techniques enable the chatbot to understand and process text inputs, categorize them based on content, determine sentiment or emotion in user messages, and generate concise summaries of lengthy text passages.
- Responsible for training the custom model and integrating the chatbot into a website using Flask.
- In parallel, I am conducting a literature review to evaluate the accuracy and potential biases of GPT models in comparison to information available on Wikipedia

### SALES ASSITANT | THREE IE (Nov 2022- June 2023)

- In my role, I successfully addressed customers' general mobile and network inquiries by providing them with tailored solutions and support. This involved engaging in meaningful conversations to ensure customers left our stores satisfied.
- Excelled in matching our extensive range of products and services to each customer's unique needs, showcasing our cutting-edge offerings and driving sales. This resulted in achieving both personal and store Key Performance Indicators (KPls).
- Also demonstrated flexibility in my work schedule, readily adapting to evenings and weekends as needed to deliver exceptional service and support to our valued customers.

# DATA ANALYST| TRUECALLER (FEB 2021 – JULY 2022)

- User Behaviour Analysis:I closely examine user behaviour patterns within the app. This involves tracking how users interact with Truecaller's features, such as call identification, spam blocking, and call recording, subscriber rate.
- Conducted churn analysis to identify common reasons for user attrition like churn, subscriber retention, This information can inform retention strategies and product improvements.
- Utilized machine learning models to enhance call identification accuracy and spam detection.
- Creating informative and visually appealing dashboards and reports is crucial for conveying insights to various stakeholders within the company.
- Developed SQL queries to obtain complex data from tables in onsite and remote databases.
- Analysed and tracked data to prepare forecasts and identify trends.

# DATA ANALYST | EDGATE TECHNOLOGIES (MARCH 2020 - JAN 2021)

- As a data analyst intern at a sme, I assisted in collecting, cleaning, and analysing data using tools like Excel and SQL. I created visualizations and reports to communicate insights and collaborate with teams on various data-related tasks.
- I assessed the effectiveness of our ARM, DSP, and FPGA processor boards, pinpointing avenues for enhancement and novel solutions. Working closely with the embedded tools development team, I meticulously scrutinize prototyping data to ensure the alignment of our hardware and software designs with performance benchmarks and industry norms.
- Worked closely with the embedded tools development team, I meticulously scrutinize
  prototyping data to ensure the alignment of our hardware and software designs with
  performance benchmarks and industry norms.

### **EDUCATION:**

MSc in Data Analytics | Dundalk Institute of Technology (2022 - 2023)

Executive Programme in Data Science | International Institute of Information Technology (2021 - 2022)

**B.E in Telecommunication and Engineering | DSCE** (2018 - 2012)

### **PROJECTS:**

### **ALGORITHMIC TRADING USING MACHINE LEARNING AND TECHNICAL ANALYSIS:**

This is my master's final dissertation project, I wanted to predict the stock market using Machine Learning and technical analysis indicator, I did so by importing the dataset from a trading broker's API and then backtesting the strategy to see if it would be profitable over time.

### **TWO WAY AUTHENTICATION FOR EXAM PAPER DETECTION:**

In India exam papers were still distributed physically and the digital era had not boomed yet and due to this the chances of an exam paper getting leaked was quite high, Hence I decided to create an electronic box with an RFID and fingerprint authentical to open the box and installed a buzzer if it was forced opened, I also implemented a GPS tracker to track its location at all time.